Elijah Rutschman

http://github.com/elijahr :: elijahr@gmail.com :: (773) 814-5185 :: 5050 N. Bernard, Chicago, IL 60625

Summary

Web developer, architect, tinkerer. I'm pragmatic, a polyglot, but with heavy expertise in Python, JavaScript and CSS.

I have worked in a fast-paced development studio, at a few start-ups, and have managed Linux servers. I've worn many hats and solved many problems in the 6 years I've worked in the field.□

I'm currently hacking on Web and mobile social content apps for Switchcam.

I hold a Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science and Philosophy from Northeastern Illinois University in Chicago.

Skills

Python JavaScript / CoffeeScript PhoneGap / Cordova

DjangoBackbone.jsgitCeleryjQueryCUNIXHTML 5 / CSS 3CythonRESTful API designResponsive layoutsPHPSQLPhotoshopCakePHP

Experience

Switchcam Software Engineer, Chicago / San Francisco, September 2012 - Present

Web and mobile development at a social content start-up.

- API design, back-end, and front-end development for Switchcam Director, a cutting-edge social video platform.
- Led the prototyping of Switchcam's video-capture mobile app and API using Django, Twitter Bootstrap, PhoneGap and Ember.js.
- Collaborated on back-end, and owned front-end development of Switchcam Agent, a platform for aggregating videos, photos, and analytics from events and concerts.

Key skills and technologies used: RESTful API design, Python/Django, Celery, Backbone.js, Ember.js, PhoneGap, and Twitter Bootstrap.

Sanders New Media Lead Django Developer, Chicago, March 2011 - September 2012

Web and mobile development at a development studio. I worked with a small team on several projects at any given time.

- Was the primary engineering contact for some of our larger clients.
- · Managed junior developers.
- Developed a Django-based e-commerce platform for a popular apparel company to enable them to scale.
- Developed highly visible Facebook games and promotions for a variety of recognizable brands to increase fan engagement.
- Owned development of Stratus, a customized CMS based on Django's admin.

Key skills and technologies used: Python/Django, Celery, Backbone.js, Twitter Bootstrap, Cocoa/Objective-C, Adobe Flex, and CakePHP.

Hagerty Consulting Software Engineer, Evanston, Jnue 2009 - March 2011

Web development at a business services start-up. I worked with a small team on Perfolio, a Web application for managing client feedback.

- Fixed bugs and implemented new front-end and back-end features.
- Migrated the platform from Windows to Linux servers.
- Converted the app to a "hashbang" URL scheme for faster browsing.
- Improved ease of navigation via AJAX-based "omnibox" style search.

Key skills and technologies used: JavaScript/jQuery, Python/Django.

MSDSonline Software Engineer, Chicago, January 2008 - June 2009

Web and Windows app development at a business services company in the Health and Safety sector.

- Worked with a medium-sized team on products for managing Material Safety Data Sheet inventory.
- Maintained existing Web and desktop software

- AJAX-based search of MSDSs to improve usability.
- JavaScript utility library written from scratch.

Key skills and technologies used: JavaScript, VB.NET, SQL.

MSDSonline / SpringCM IT Engineer, Chicago, June 2006 - January 2008

Managed Windows and Linux servers, responded to helpdesk tickets, and provisioned desktops and laptops for new employees.

Education

Northeastern Illinois University Chicago

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science, Philosophy 2004 - 2008

Honors: Dean's List (for maintaining a 3.75 or higher GPA)

Antioch College Yellow Springs, OH

Creative Writing 2002 - 2004